Fatmir Likrama

Houston, TX +1 832 341 8513 limanoa@gmail.com https://flikrama.github.io/

DevOps, Analytics and Energy professional experienced in software development, technical consulting, data analysis/statistics and project management. Analytical background in Physics and Engineering with proven communication and business skills.

Skills

- More than 10 years of experience as a product manager, consultant and technical analyst converting technical and market expertise to business value.
- Agile/Scrum practitioner.
- User of SQL and Python with big data in a business and technical environment.
- Experience with Power BI and Tableau analysis, dashboard creation and maintenance, familiar with geospatial technology.
- Proven verbal and written communication and team building skills.

Employment Experience

Product Manager: Boston Scientific 7/2021 - Present Houston, TX

- Determined customer needs and desires by market research and specified market requirements for current and future products
- Worked with R&D to define the product release requirements
- Defined product strategy and roadmap
- Determined and prioritized the product requirements
- Delivered Marketing Requirements Documents (MRDs) and Product Requirements Documents (PRDs) with prioritized features and corresponding justification
- Worked closely with R&D Architects, Managers, and Leads to ensure product direction is being carried forward as intended
- Developed an integrated plan for market introduction
- Brought new products to market by analyzing product requirements and product development programs, preparing ROI analyses, and establishing schedules / timelines with R&D and Marketing.

Contractor Research Specialist, Texas DSHS: Data Analytics Team 9/2020 - 7/2021 Austin, TX Lead

- Performed forecasting, segmentation studies and ad hoc analytics on Texas immunization coverage and data exchange with the immunization registry.
- Testing, developing and presenting SQL procedures, automation tools, standard operating procedures for accurate and complete data streaming for bi-directional data streaming system.
- Led the Immunization Registry Data Analytics Team by helping members achieve objectives and grow professionally.

Rock Physics Product Owner Landmark Software, Halliburton

6/2019 - 5/2020

Houston, TX

- Managed a rock physics products software portfolio within an Agile framework.
- Maintained product backlog balancing the requirements of stakeholders and clients
- Built, documented, tracked and approved mockups, test cases and acceptance criteria.
- Built and maintained relationships with clients and stakeholders for requirements and input.

Consultant/Product Manager Halliburton Consulting

5/2012 - 6/2019

Houston, TX

- Delivered data driven solutions with a customer-first mindset
- Performed Geomechanics Consulting/Analytics, Project Management and business development work for oil and gas operators all around the globe.
- Translated technical content into actionable business items for management review and decision making.
- Managed software development of proprietary connector transferring data between geological to FEM platforms

Engineering Intern Schlumberger

5/2007 - 9/2007

Sugar Land, TX

Modeled mud filtrate invasion, fluid flow to a sampling probe and drilling mud filtrate clean up in a Wireline Formation Testing utilizing Eclipse 300 Reservoir modelling software.

Research Assistant University of Texas at Austin

6/2006-12/2008

Austin, TX

Collaborated in research on coupled fluid dynamics and mechanics of weakly cemented and uncemented formations, permeability variation, stress and fracture reorientation and wellbore failure analysis modeling.

Education

University of Texas at Austin, Master of Science in Engineering,

8/2006 - 12/2008

Austin, TX

Thesis: Study of Mechanical and Flow Properties of Weakly Cemented and Un-cemented Sands Using Discrete Element Method Modeling.

Boğaziçi University, Bachelor of Science, Physics 9/1999 - 6/2003

Istanbul, Turkey

Graduated ranking top of 2003 class, Physics Department.

US Citizen since 2015